Guide to the Peter Palmquist Collection of Women in Photography
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Women in Photography International Records, 1980-2003; Series IV; (14 boxes)
  - Event Materials
    This subseries is organized chronologically followed by materials that have dimensions greater than 22 x 29 cm (8.7 x 14.5 in.), which is also organized chronologically.
    This subseries consists mainly of materials that document events sponsored by Women in Photography International, including promotional material and products from the events as well as photographs of events and attendees. This subseries includes a complete travelling photography exhibition, "Women in Photography International," organized by the group, which toured from November 1989 to January 1991.
    - Events and exhibitions, circa 1982-1989 (Box 462, Folder 3507)
    - Women Photographers in America, 1985, 1 photographic print and 32 35mm negatives (Box 462, Folder 3508)
    - Getting Published, a presentation by Kenna Love, 1987 Jan; 9 photographic prints and 14 35mm negatives (Box 462, Folder 3509)
    - Women in Photography International Open House, 1987 Jul (Box 462, Folder 3510)
    - Women Photographers in America, 1987, 8 photographic prints, 37 35mm negatives, and 13 color 35mm slides (Box 462, Folder 3511)
    - Foto Fashion '88, a presentation by Victoria Pearson and Susan Nygeres, 1988 Oct 18 (Box 462, Folder 3512)
    - Women in Photography International, 1989 Nov-1991 Jan; 16 color photographic prints and 14 color 35mm negatives (Box 462, Folder 3513)
    - Women in Photography Celebrates Freedom, 1992 Jan-Feb (Box 462, Folder 3514)
    - Tea Time: Images of Women, Images of Tea, 2001 (Box 462, Folder 3515)
      Copies of a CD-ROM that accompanied this exhibition are available in the Audiovisual Materials subseries in Series II.
    - Hollywood Bound, 2002 Jan-Mar (Box 462, Folder 3516)
    - Kitsch & Klick: The Art of the Toy Camera, 2002 Mar-Apr (Box 462, Folder 3517)
    - photo l.a.: 12th International Los Angeles Photographic Print Exposition, 2003 Jan (Box 462, Folder 3518)
    - Oversize Event Material
      - Women Photographers, 1984; 3 posters (Box 463, Folder 3519)
      - Women Photographers in America, 1985, 5 posters (Box 463, Folder 3520)
      - Women Photographers in America, 1987, 2 posters (Box 463, Folder 3521)
      - The Visual Statement: A Photographic Lecture Series, 1989 Apr; 1 poster (Box 463, Folder 3522)
      - Women in Photography International (Exhibition)
        - Zoom: The International Image Magazine, Volume 42, 1989 Oct; 1 serial (Box 463, Folder 3523)
        - Publicity, 1989-1991; 1 poster and 1 flier (Box 463, Folder 3524)
        - Photographic Prints, 1989; 34 photographic prints and 35 color photographic prints in 8 oversize obxes
          The following photographs comprised the entire Women in Photography international exhibition.
          - Abramson, Barbara, 1 color photographic print (Box 464, Folder 3525)
            Also known as Bobbie Abramson
          - Almquist, Anki, 1 photographic print (Box 464, Folder 3526)
          - Altman, Lynn, 1 photographic print (Box 464, Folder 3527)
          - Barnes, Evelyn, 1 photographic print (Box 464, Folder 3528)
          - Baylis, Michele Jan, 1 color photographic print (Box 464, Folder 3529)
          - Berry, Carolyn (born 1930), 1 color photographic print (Box 464, Folder 3530)
          - Blake, Nan Standish (born 1943), 1 color photographic print (Box 464, Folder 3531)
            Also known as Nan Blake, Nan Blake-Norvell, or Norvell-Nan
          - Blickle, Alayne Renée (born 1955), 1 photographic print (Box 464, Folder 3532)
          - Bokharai, Afarin Radjaei, 1 color photographic print (Box 464, Folder 3533)
            Also known as Afarin Radjaie
          - Bondi, Darlene, 1 color photographic print (Box 464, Folder 3534)
          - Bullock, Edna (1915-1997), 1 photographic print (Box 464, Folder 3535)
          - Chase, Christina, 1 photographic print (Box 465, Folder 3536)
          - Collins, Judith, 1 photographic print (Box 465, Folder 3537)
          - Donovan, Patty, 1 color photographic print (Box 465, Folder 3538)
          - Duchesne-Peckham, Judy, 1 color photographic print (Box 465, Folder 3539)
          - Duffy, Pamela, 2 photographic prints (Box 465, Folder 3540-3541)
          - Duncan, Patricia DuBose, 1 color photographic print (Box 465, Folder 3542)
            Also known as Patricia Dubose-Duncan
          - Edelman, Joyce Alexis, 1 color photographic print (Box 466, Folder 3543)
          - Edwards, Althea, 1 color photographic print (Box 466, Folder 3544)
          - Ekström, Kirsten, 1 photographic print (Box 466, Folder 3545)
          - Enderlein, Eva, 1 photographic print (Box 466, Folder 3546)
          - Flamer, Bonnie, 1 photographic print (Box 466, Folder 3547)
          - Gibson, Bernadette F. P., 4 color photographic prints (Box 467, Folder 3548-3551)
          - Glickman, Judy Ellis, 1 photographic print (Box 467, Folder 3552)
          - Goldsmith, Lynn, 1 photographic print (Box 467, Folder 3553)
          - Green, Sharon, 1 photographic print (Box 467, Folder 3554)
          - Gruber, Aaronel deRoy (born 1918), 1 color photographic print (Box 467, Folder 3555)
          - Halsay, Gina, 1 photographic print (Box 468, Folder 3556)
          - Hardin, Kathy Corday, 1 photographic print (Box 468, Folder 3557)
          - Joseph, Linda, 1 color photographic print (Box 468, Folder 3558)
          - Kahl, Leslie R., 1 color photographic print (Box 468, Folder 3559)
          - Kessler, Shari, 1 color photographic print (Box 468, Folder 3560)
          - Knott, Janet, 1 photographic print (Box 468, Folder 3561)
          - Krasner, Carin, 1 color photographic print (Box 468, Folder 3562)
          - Krieg, Carolyn, 1 color photographic print (Box 468, Folder 3563)
          - Lapides, Susan, 1 color photographic print (Box 469, Folder 3564)
          - Lupis, Odette, 1 photographic print (Box 469, Folder 3565)
          - Lutchford, Ann E., 1 photographic print (Box 469, Folder 3566)
          - Mack, Marcia, 1 color photographic print (Box 469, Folder 3567)
          - Mandolf, Judy, 1 color photographic print (Box 469, Folder 3568)
          - Marcotte, Denise, 1 color photographic print (Box 469, Folder 3569)
          - Marenzi, Loredana, 1 color photographic print (Box 469, Folder 3570)
          - Mazza, Patricia, 1 color photographic print (Box 469, Folder 3571)
          - McCullough, Olivia B., 1 color photographic print (Box 470, Folder 3572)
          - Meredith, Ann P., 2 photographic prints (Box 470, Folder 3573-3574)
          - Noren, Catherine Hanf (born 1938), 1 color photographic print (Box 470, Folder 3575)
          - Nye, Carol, 1 photographic print (Box 470, Folder 3576)
          - Regen, Stephanie, 1 color photographic print (Box 470, Folder 3577)
          - Ropion, Adeline, 1 color photographic print (Box 470, Folder 3578)
          - Rossa, Della, 1 photographic print (Box 470, Folder 3579)
          - Roth, Joan (born 1942), 1 color photographic print (Box 470, Folder 3580)
          - Sawyer, Carol (born 1961), 1 photographic print (Box 471, Folder 3581)
          - Schipper, Janet, 1 photographic print (Box 471, Folder 3582)
          - Scianghetti, Bärbel M., 2 photographic prints (Box 471, Folder 3583-3584)
          - Silberberg, Susan, 1 color photographic print (Box 471, Folder 3585)
          - Simonite, Patricia, 1 color photographic print (Box 471, Folder 3586)
          - Singleton, Chris, 1 color photographic print (Box 471, Folder 3587)
          - Stevens, Jane M. (born 1947), 1 photographic print (Box 471, Folder 3588)
          - Switz, Helen Feyler, 4 photographic prints on 1 mount (Box 471, Folder 3589)
          - Valandani, Val, 1 photographic print and 1 poster (Box 472, Folder 3590)
      - Tea Time: Images of Women, Images of Tea, 2001; 1 poster (Box 463, Folder 3591)
- Additions from Other Collections, Series IV
  - Biographical Materials
    - Biographical Files
      - Bartlett, N. Gray, Mrs. (Box 473)
      - Everhard, Mary E. (Box 473)
      - Glauber, Carole (Box 473)
      - Jones, Grace Hubley (Box 473)
      - Larrabee, Constance Stuart (Box 473)
      - Nguyen, Trinh (Box 473)
      - Omori, Emiko (Box 473)
      - Yang, Ruby (Box 473)
  - Photographic Materials
    - Simms, Leona, 7 (Box 474)
    - Trowbridge, Eunice (Box 474)
    - Unidentified photographer, probably from Oakland, California, 1925-1926 (Box 474)
  - Photograph Albums
    - Brogden, Penny, 2013 (Box 475)
      Immediate Source of Acquisition
      Gift of Penny Brogden, 2014
      Copy of her, Native Son: Artist's Book, copy 4 of 8
    - Greene, Hanna C. (Box 476)
    - Simms, Leona (Box 477)
    - Simms, Leona (Box 478)
    - Simms, Leona (Box 479)
    - __________, Barbara, circa 1950-1985 (Box 480)
  - Oversize Photographic Material
    - Darling, Bella, circa 1900 (Box 481 (Oversize))
    - Freeman, Emma (Box 482 (Oversize))
    - Horn, Grace Chandler, 34 (Box 481 (Oversize))
    - Kubes, Amy (Box 483 (Broadside oversize))
    - Mitchell, Margaretta K. (Box 484 (Broadside oversize))
    - Nestor, Helen (Box 485 (Oversize))
    - Růžičková, Petra (Box 486 (Broadside oversize))
  - Publication and Exhibition Research Files
    - Original cartoons related to women's rights, 1874-circa 1900; 5 (Box 487 (Oversize))
    - Photocopies of photographs of women (Box 488)
    - Women in Photography International Archive: Biographical Sketches and Inventory, drafts, 17 (Box 489)
    - Women in Photography International Archive: Miscellaneous Research Materials, 1998-2002, 8 (Box 490)
    - Women Photographers: Miscellaneous advertisements and illsutrations from periodical literature, 1870-1970, bound volume (Box 488)
- July 2015 acquisition, 1975-2017; 43.33; 34 boxes
  The 2015 addition consists of organizational records of Women in Photography International (WIPI), event and exhibition materials, photographic prints, correspondence, printed materials (including both periodicals and photographer books), and electronic files. Materials in this addition were compiled by Jean Ferro, who served as President of WIPI from 2000 to 2016.
  - Records, 1985-2015
    - Biographical files, membership lists, programs, press, promo samples, website startup files, 1985-2008; 11 folders (Box 491)
      - Electronic media, 22 (Box 521)
        Box 521 (digital media): Restricted fragile material. Access copies of digital files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
      - Electronic media, 1 external harddrive, 39 3.5" disks, 1 zip disk (Box 523)
        Box 523 (digital media): Restricted fragile material. Access copies of digital files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
      - iMac desktop computer and accessories
        Restricted fragile material. Access copies of digital files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - Women in Photography International archive reference binder, 2016- (Box 492)
      - Electronic media, 1 (Box 522)
        Box 522 (digital media): Restricted fragile material. Access copies of digital files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - Member correspondence and promotional material addressed to Jean Ferro or WIPI, 1991-2005; 5 folders (Box 491)
      - Print sent in by Jane Olin with enclosed correspondence and photobooks, 2015- (Box 493)
      - Prints sent in by Carol Bishop (16x20), 2005-; 1 folder (Box 494)
      - Audiovisual material, 2013-2014, undated; 3; 1 (Box 521, Box 524)
        Boxes 524 (audiovisual material): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information
      - Electronic media, 1 (Box 522)
    - Women In Photography International sign, 1 folder (Box 494)
  - Event materials, 2001-2015
    - Tea Time: Images of Women, Images of Tea, 20th Anniversary, 2001-
      - Production files, photographer bios, CD/poster design files, expenses, submission forms and low resolution images, 2001-; 15 folders (Box 495)
      - Posters, CD covers, and proofs (16x20), 2001-; 2 folders (Box 494)
      - Electronic media, 2001-; 21 (Box 521)
      - Electronic media, 2001-; 15 (Box 523)
        Box 523(digital media): Restricted fragile material. Access copies of digital files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
      - Exhibition prints
        The following photographers' prints are represented in these boxes: Alt, Jane Fulton; Bebe, Shahla; Bogle, Jan; Botkin, Liza Hennessey; Lamaina, Lucia Suzun; Donald, Mary McCartney; Drucker, Jennifer; Ferraro, Jane Foley; Ferro, Jean; Golden, Gloria; Halek, Judith Elaine; Harper, Patricia; Hotchkiss, Rachel; Hunt, Marilyn; Kenneday, Elizabeth; McLemore, Julia; MacLeod, Kate; Nicholl, Jamie; Nye, Carol; Vanderford-Pfaff, Amie; Pulga, Patrizia; Romais, Miriam; Sapountzi, Aliki; Sarri, Fanny; Sartor, Margaret; Sasaki, Kanako; Seligman, Sharon; Sokolow, Leslie; Villines, Carrie; Von Eckardt, Barbara; Whitcomb, Laine; White, Sylvia
        - Exhibition prints (14x18), 2001-; 6 folders (Box 496)
        - Exhibition prints (20x24), 2001-; 5 folders (Box 497)
        - Exhibition prints (20x24), 2001-; 5 folders (Box 498)
        - Exhibition prints (20x24), 2001-; 6 folders (Box 499)
        - Exhibition prints (20x24), 2001-; 6 folders (Box 500)
        - Exhibition prints (20x24), 2001-; 6 folders (Box 501)
        - Exhibition prints (20x24), 2001-; 5 folders (Box 502)
        - Exhibition prints (22x28), 2001-; 5 folders (Box 503)
        - Exhibition prints (22x28), 2001-; 4 folders (Box 504)
        - Extra Tea Time prints (22x28), 2001-; 1 folder (Box 502)
    - Juried competitions/exhibitions, 2002-2006; 7 folders (Box 495)
      - Electronic media, 5 (Box 521)
      - Electronic media, 2 CDS; 1 zip disk (Box 522)
    - Photo L.A. files
      - 2002-2015, 14 folders (Box 505)
      - 2004, 6 folders (Box 506)
      - Electronic media, 3 (Box 521)
        Box 521(digital media): Restricted fragile material. Access copies of digital files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
      - Oversized Photo L.A. material
        - WIPI Photo L.A. exhibition booth banner (43"x74"), 2014- (Box 507)
        - "Put Yourself in the Picture," WIPI interactive collage installation mirror (16x16), 2015- (Box 508)
        - "Put Yourself in the Picture," WIPI collage backdrop (42"x60"), 2015- (Box 509)
    - Lucie Awards, 2003-2014; 3 folders (Box 495)
      - Electronic media, 2 (Box 521)
    - Turning Silver, 25th Anniversary exhibition, 2006-
      - Production files, release and submission forms, juror packets., 2006-; 9 folders (Box 495)
      - Electronic media, 75 (Box 522)
        Box 522(digital media): Restricted fragile material. Access copies of digital files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
      - Exhibition prints, 2006-
        - Exhibition prints, 2006-; 8 folders (Box 510)
        - Exhibition prints (14x18), 2006-; 5 folders (Box 511)
        - Juror 100 box (20x24), 2006-; 4 folders (Box 512)
        - Submitted but not chosen archive (16x20), 2006-; 6 folders (Box 513)
    - Juried competitions/exhibitions, 2007-2013; 11 folders (Box 514)
      - Electronic media, 2 (Box 521)
      - Electronic media, 9 (Box 522)
  - Printed material
    - Distinguished photographer books, 1975-2017
      Books were arranged alphabetically by the photographer whose work the volume featured or described, if ascertained, and, when unsure, by the title. Many of these volumes are inscribed to Jean Ferro (WIPI President, 2000-2016), for inclusion in WIPI archives. Any enclosed correspondence was foldered and placed behind the volume from which it was removed.
      - A-Carr, 1991-2015 (Box 515)
        Photographers' works represented in this box include: Abbott, Berenice; Addario, Lynsey; Almond, Joan; Alt, Jane Fulton; Bigbee, Ivy; Cameron, Julia Margaret; Carr, Kathleen.
      - Connelly-Harvey, 1975-2015 (Box 516)
        Photographers' works represented in this box include: Connelly, Jill; Corday, Kathy; Cunningham, Imogene; Dater, Judy; Fastman, Raisa; Ferro, Jean; Findhorn Community; Fleischman, J.D.; Goldstein, Ann; Gottlieb, Jane; Greenblatt, Cathy; Harvey, Andrew
      - Hofkin-Orkin, 1978-2015 (Box 517)
        Photographers' works represented in this box include: Hofkin, Ann Ginsburgh; Homans, Katy; Imboden, Connie; Johnson, Jamie; Lumme, Helena; Madison, Meg; Meiser, Winifred; Miller, Freyda; Mitchell, Margaretta; Orkin, Ruth
      - Peck-Riviera, 1990-2017 (Box 518)
        Photographers' works represented in this box include: Peck, Mary; Press, Betty; Pulga, Patrizia; Richards, Patricia; Riviera, Patrizia
      - Sacco - The Way Home, 1989-2015 (Box 519)
        Photographers' works respresented in this box include: Sacco, Graciela; Squires, Wilda; Stieglitz, Alfred; Stevens, Jane; Tenneson, Joyce; Vial, Veronique; The Way Home
      - Photography periodicals and catalogs, 1981-2015, undated (Box 519)
        Volumes and issues of the following periodicals and catalogs are represented: The Blatant Image, Clickers and Flickers, 2008-2014, Division Leap, Polaroid Guide to Instant Imaging, Portfolio, A Guide to the Arts and Artists of the East End, Printed Matter's LA Book Fair catalogs (2013, 2015), Professional Women Photographers, Silvershotz, The Society for Photographic Education: resource guide and membership directory 1998, Test magazine, and Zoom. Catalogs: LA Art Book Fair, WestLicht Photographic Auction.
      - Oversized distinguished photographer books, 1987-2015 (Box 520)
        Photographers' works respresented in this box include: Butler, Linda; Davis, Margo; Fastman, Raisa; Heureux, J.J.L.; Kitchen, E. F.; Newman, Cathy; Sicilia Singolare Femminile, Siegfried, Elizabeth; Terry, Sarah.